C.U.VIVEK PERFORMANCE TEST ENGINEER

Contact:

Emaild: vivekcu81@gmail.com LinkendIn: linkedin.com/in/vivekcu

Phone: +91-8124488750



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY.

Performance Test Engineer with over 4 years of experience in Performance Testing and Engineering. Experience in Telecom and Petroleum Domain. E2E Project Experience, Designing NFT Test Strategies, Execution and Analysing critical business requirements.

Experience in performance testing/analysis of Microservice based application. Hands on exposure to Kubernetes and Openshift. Performance scripting exeperience using Jmeter and Loadrunner.

AWS & Azure certified having experience of performance testing products hosted in cloud.



WORK EXPERIENCE.

Performance Test Engineer Amdocs India LLC, Pune

November 2019 - Present

- Part of Microservices based Digital Application NFT Testing Team in Amdocs Core (R&D division).
- Agile based monthly drop release Application Testing and Certification on various platforms like Openshift (Kubernetes), AWS EKS environment.
- End to End Performance Test Execution, Monitoring, Test Result Analysis and Profiling of Microservice based application using Jmeter, Kubernetes, Openshift, Couchbase, Kafka, Prometheus, Grafana and AWS services like EC2, RDS, Cloudwatch, EBS, MSK.
- Identifying potential bottlenecks in system by conducting different tests like Load Test, Stress Test, Stability Test, Scalability Test, HA & Failover Test, Chaos Monkey Test.
- Profiling and Heap/Thread Dump analysis using different APM Tools like Dynatrace, JProfiler, JVisualVm etc.
- Co-ordinate with various stakeholders (Architects, Product Owners and Hardware Procurement teams) for sizing of production systems based on performance test results.

Software Test Engineer Petrolink Data Services Pvt. Ltd., Pune July 2019 - October 2019

- Gather Non-Functional requirements from the product team.Create and review Performance Test Plan.
- Develop performance test script as per traversal flow document using Jmeter.
- Execute various test runs like Load, Stress, Endurance, Fail over.
- Monitor CPU and Memory utilization of application server to ensure no performance bottlenecks are occurring.



Develop test scripts using protocols - Web (HTTP/HTML),

- Web Services in Loadrunner.

 Performing Admin tasks for Stormrunner tool which
- included processes like tracking and solving execution related issues, setup of SRL in load generators.
- Create load/stress/endurance/Isolated & other non-functional tests scenarios & execute them.
- Performance testing post-test tasks: Analyze the CPU Utilization, Memory usage using Dynatrace to verify the performance of the applications.
- Monitor application logs to determine application behavior, generate performance graphs and other related documents required for validation & analysis.

SKILLS.

- Openshift, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Azure and Microservice
- Postgres, Couchbase, Python, Shell Scripting
- Microfocus Loadrunner and Apache Jmeter
- Protocols: Web (HTTP/HTML), Web Services and Websocket
- HP Performance center 11.52, Microfocus Stormrunner Load
- Dynatrace, Grafana, Prometheus, JvisualVM, Jconsole and Perfmon.
- Heap Dump, Thread dump and GC analysis.
- Fiddler, SoapUI, Postman
- HP Quality Center 11.52, JIRA, Confluene

CERTIFICATIONS.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate(SAA)

September 2020 - September 2023

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - (CLF) October 2020 - October 2023

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Certification number: H493-4472

EDUCATION.

B.Tech - Civil Engineering, CGPA - 8.73/10 VIT University, Vellore, Tamil Nadu 2012-2016

HSC(12th) - 81.00% Delhi Public School, Bhilai, Chhattisgarh 2012

SSLC(10th) - 93.10% Delhi Public School, Bhilai, Chhattisgarh 2010

PERSONAL DETAILS.

Date of Birth : 13-10-1993 Nationality : Indian Father's Name : Mr. C.N. Ullas

Languages Known: English, Hindi and Malayalam

Passport Status : Valid

Address : 8D, Street - 36, Sector 10, Bhilai

Chhattisgarh, 490006